<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of the contractors with the Czar of Moscovy, for the sole importation of tobacco into his dominions.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01899</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1053</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224751</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52211943</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52211943</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175511</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01899)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175511)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2739:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of the contractors with the Czar of Moscovy, for the sole importation of tobacco into his dominions.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Half-title on p. [2]: The case of the contractors with the C'zar of Muscovy, for importing of tobacco into Russia.</note>
                  <note>Publication data suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Lincoln's Inn Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tobacco industry --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Export controls --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Commerce --  Russia --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Russia --  Commerce --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:175511:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 40 -->
            <head>The CASE of the Contractors with the C'ZAR of <hi>MOSCOVY,</hi> for the <hi>Sole Importation of Tobacco</hi> into his Dominions.</head>
            <p>THEY were incouraged to enter into a Treaty with the Czar for a Free Importation of Tobacco into his Dominions, by a BILL that was Depending in the Houſe of Commons for Inlarging the Trade to <hi>Ruſſia,</hi> by an Eaſie Admiſſion into the Freedom of that Company; and they deferred the Concluding any Abſolute Agreement, till the BILL had paſſed that Houſe, and had Deferred it till it had Paſſed the Houſe of Lords and the Royal Aſſent, but that the C'zar and his Miniſters, were then upon their Departure.</p>
            <p>They thought a Thing of that Nature, ſo greatly and unqueſtionably Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantageous to this Kingdom, and by which no Man's Property was Invaded (becauſe the BILL made no Alteration in their Charter, but only fixed the Fine for Admiſſion; which neither their Charter nor the Act of Parliament that Confirmed it, takes any notice of) would not have met with any Oppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition.</p>
            <p>They paid the C'zar 12000 <hi>l.</hi> immediately upon Signing the Contract, and it coſt them above 1000 <hi>l.</hi> more in other Charges to obtain it; and this they did before one half of the Sum was ſubſcribed that was intended for a Stock ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient to Carry on the Trade. But when the BILL was oppoſed, all further Subſcriptions ceaſed; every body being ſenſible that without a Freedom of the <hi>Ruſſia</hi> Company, the Trade could not be Carried on to any Advantage; and unleſs the Terms of Admiſſion were very eaſie, thoſe Perſons that were but lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle concerned in the Tobacco Contract, would not take their Freedom: And except every Man concerned were Free, the Trade could not be driven: thus the whole Burthen of that Undertaking fell upon the Shoulders of Seven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty or Eighty Perſons, who were the Firſt Subſcribers; and ſome of thoſe up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the fore-mentioned Diſcouragements, do refuſe to pay their Proportion of the 13000 <hi>l.</hi> or be any ways concerned in the Trade.</p>
            <p>Nevertheleſs the reſt thought it needful to ſend ſome Tobacco, and thereby ſhew their willingneſs to Comply with their part of the Contract, leſt the C'zar ſhould take an Advantage by their Neglect, and ſo they might loſe the 12000 <hi>l.</hi> paid Him, and all their other Charges; and the Nation the Advantage of that Liberty which had been ſo long deſired.</p>
            <p>But the BILL not paſſing, and the <hi>Ruſſia</hi> Company having power to ſeize any Engliſhmens Ships and Goods that Trade to <hi>Ruſſia</hi> without their Licence, they could not ſend any Tobacco from hence directly for <hi>Archangel,</hi> the only Port of <hi>Ruſſia:</hi> Therefore they ordered about 110000 Pounds of <hi>Virginia</hi> Leaf (that were firſt ſent from <hi>London</hi> to <hi>Holland</hi>) to be ſent from <hi>Holland</hi> thi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther. What more they could get ready for that Seaſon, which was about 180000 Pounds of Role and Cut Tobacco, with Tobacco Pipes, Boxes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> they were forced to ſend from hence by way of <hi>Narva,</hi> a Sweeds Port; which
<pb facs="tcp:175511:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 41 -->
hath proved very prejudicial to them, becauſe the Sweeds demand upon the Role 17, and upon the Cut 34, <hi>per Cent.</hi> Cuſtom, according to the true value: all which might have been ſaved, if they had had Liberty to have ſent it direct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to <hi>Archangel.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Their Factors in <hi>Ruſſia</hi> have ſold part of the Tobacco that was ſent them, and write that in a few years a very conſiderable Quantity may be Vended there; but being a New Thing, it will require Time and a great Charge, to put it into a Right Method, and make it Diffuſive throughout that Vaſt Empire.</p>
            <p>They hope their Undertaking being of ſuch National Advantage, and by which they have at preſent ſo little Proſpect of Profit to themſelves, will meet with all due Incouragement from the Publick.</p>
            <p>If they cannot obtain their Freedom of the <hi>Ruſſia</hi> Company this Seſſions, upon Moderate Terms, they ſhall not be able to Comply with their Contract with the C'zar, but muſt be forced to throw up their Patent, or diſpoſe of it to the Dutch on the beſt Terms they can; for the <hi>Ruſſia</hi> Company will neither make uſe of it themſelves (tho the Contractors have proffered it them and a Large Sum of Money, to accept of it) nor ſuffer others to do it, that would, except upon ſuch Conditions as cannot be Complied with.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:175511:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 42 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
